

■ me@cheukwing.dev | 😭 cheukwing | 🛅 cheukwing

Summary_

Final year Imperial College student with a range of experiences in computer science from education, industry, and the wider community - including contributions to open source, teaching to young students, and development of applications from idea to product. Has a particular interest in distributed systems and functional programming.

Education _____

Imperial College London

Londoi

MENG IN COMPUTING (PREDICTED FIRST CLASS)

Oct 2016 - Jun 2020

- · Modules include: 81% Type Systems, 81% Distributed Algorithms, 79% Information and Coding Theory.
- Engineering **Dean's List** for top 10% performance in second year.
- Won Morgan Stanley Prize for top 12 first year students.

Work Experience _____

Jetstack Lon

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN Apr 2019 - Sep 2019

- Completely rewrote the frontend of Flightdeck (a web application for Kubernetes training) to Elm best practices, facilitating and subsequently supporting the onboarding of a new frontend engineer.
- Contributed to Cert-Manager, the open source Kubernetes project for managing TLS certificates, becoming the 5th top contributor at the time.
- Co-led the design and implementation of *Aerodrome*, a platform for the provisioning of arbitrary environments to host *Flightdeck* training scenarios upon, building **Kubernetes controllers** in **Go** and making thorough use of **Docker** and **Google Cloud**, cutting the running cost of *Flightdeck* versus the existing third party service.
- · Participated in bi-weekly sprint planning, sprint retrospectives, and daily stand-ups, gaining industrial experience of Agile development.

Ocado Technology Hatfield

Technology Intern Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Connected together several pieces of sensor hardware with several **computer vision** libraries to develop a single **C++** library with which to track the real time movements of a person.
- Developed the library into an **Electron** application *robot-video-conf*, transmitting and mapping the movements to a remote, life-size, robotic upper body to make video conferencing more engaging and interactive.

Projects_____

Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA)

Available on GitHub

THIRD YEAR GROUP PROJECT

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

- As a group of 6, developed a rule-based NLP solution for the extraction and storage of entity-attribute pairs with their calculated sentiment
 from news articles using Python, streamlining the work of a financial analyst by providing easy access to aggregated sentiment and relevant
 quotations for companies of interest.
- Further showcased the use of the solution by building a demo application with a **RESTful Python** backend and **React** frontend.

Lembas Available on Request

WEBAPPS GROUP PROJECT

Jun 201

- In a group of 4, developed a full stack **React/Node/PostgreSQL** web application for the creation and sharing of meal plans, helping to combat the issue of unbalanced diets by providing a method of communication between nutritionists and everyday people.
- Implemented **human-centered-design** techniques including user stories and micro-iterations from demoing and surveying potential users, ensuring all committed changes were improvements to the user experience.

Extracurricular Activity _____

Imperial College London (Department of Computing)

Londo

PERSONAL PROGRAMMING TUTOR

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

- Ran a weekly tutorial with a group of 8 first-year students to supplement their **Haskell** and **Java** learning, expanding their knowledge of algorithms and good software design practices.
- · Marked and gave feedback to weekly assignments, highlighting mistakes and ways to improve.

Robogals London L

Training Manager Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

- Regularly volunteered to teach classes of schoolchildren in workshops to program Lego robots, introducing them to the basics of programming.
- · Prepared and led training days to on-board new volunteers, simultaneously also introducing many to programming as well.
- · Designed new workshops and teaching materials to increase the range of skills taught by the society.